Guide to the Edwards Pierrepont Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Special Files, 1813-1902; Series II; 1'(3 boxes)
  - Cases
    - Pierrepont, Edwards, accounting as executor, estate of Edwards, Alfred H.P., 1860 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Pierrepont, Edwards, executor v. Edwards, Mary G., Edwards, John M.; Hoyt, William S. and Frances, Hooker, Worthington and Henrietta, 1861-1863 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Rhinelander, William C.; Boanman, James; Rogers, George P.; Stewart, [Lisperraro?]; State, Oliver Jr.; Clarke, Albert; Pierrepont, Edwards and Roberts, Marshall O. v. the Mayor etc. of the City of New York, 1862 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Roberts, Susan L. and Patterson, John F., executors of the will of Roberts, Marshall O. v. Dickerson, Edward N., 1888 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Riley, Patrick v. Steele, Franklin, 1871 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Smith, Isaac N. and Noble, Charles v. Ellis, Robert and Ellis, Thomas P., 1855 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Stuyvesant, Nicholas W. v. Hanrahan, John and Lake, Joseph T. et al, undated (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Thayer, Erastus D. v. Willet, James C., sherriff etc., undated (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Thomson, Charles v. Sixpenny Savings Bank, undated (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - U.S. v. Forbes, Paul S. et al, 1866 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - U.S. v. Phelps, Royal et al, 1869 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - U.S. v. Smith, Thomas E., 1868 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - U.S. v. [Whinsster?] et al, undated (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Westcot, Joseph H. v. Ellis, Robert and Ellis, Thomas P., 1854, 1857 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Willets, Samuel in re. probate of the alleged last will and testament of, 1883 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - [Willite?] John v. Sutton, John, undated (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Willoughby, Samuel A. v. Rentz, Frederick (President of Mechanics Banking Association), 1848 (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Winant, Daniel D. v. Phelan, Michael, 1856 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Estates
    - Dolan, Rose: Pierrepont, Edwards appointed administrator of estate, and guardian of Dolan, Mary R., 1860 (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Edwards, Alfred H. P. (Pierrepont, Edwards as executor): papers, miscellaneous, 1856-60, 1869, 1878 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Financial
    - Insurance Certificates, 1855-56, 1862-1870, 1873 (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - Promisary notes etc. and protests, 1846, 1851-54, 1859, 1867-1871, 1876 (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - Receipts - miscellaneous and unidentified, 1846-59, 1865-1871 (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - Receipts - Pierrepont, Edwards, 1853, 1862-1869 (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - Receipts - Pierrepont, Edwards, 1870-1887, undated (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - Receipts - Pierrepont, Mrs. Edwards, 1871-72, 1875 (Box 7, Folder 60)
    - Receipts - Pierrepont, Mrs. Edwards, 1876-78, 1888, 1893 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Legal material
    - Miscellaneous, 1813, 1849-1884 (Box 7, Folder 62)
      - Oversize material (Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Newspaper clippings
    - Concerning Pierrepont, Edwards and Dix, John A., undated (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - Concerning American - British Relations, undated (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Passport
    - Spanish, Pierrepont, Edwards, 1853 (Box 7, Folder 65)
      - Oversize material (Folder 8)
  - Printed matter
    - Miscellaneous, 1859, 1872, undated (Box 7, Folder 66)
      - Oversize material (Folder 8)
  - Proclamations
    - Grant, Ulysses Simpson, Concerning the Mississippi crisis, 1874, 1875 (Box 7, Folder 67)
      - Oversize material (Folder 8)
  - Reports
    - Respecting the late industrial conflicts in the United States, presented to both Houses of Parliament by command of Her Majesty (printed), 1877 (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - The Erie Railway and its relations with the Atlantic and Great Western and the Cleveland, Columbus, Cincinnati and Indianapolis Railways (printed), 1874 (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - To the proprietors of the Erie and Atlantic and Great Western Railways (printed), 1876 (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - Statutes
    - Revised, concerning the office of Attorney-General (copy), undated (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - Subscription list
    - To "University" by Yale graduates, including Pierrepont, Edwards and Evarts, William M. (copy), undated (Box 7, Folder 71)
- Calendar of Selected Correspondence from Series I
  This calendar provides additional information about selected correspondence in boxes 1-3 in Series I in this collection. The additional accession to this collection also contains correspondence that is not included in this calendar. The calendar was completed as part of the original processing of the collection, and it is unclear what criteria were used to determine which correspondence was further described (calendared) and which was not.
  - Ames, Adelbert, 1835-1933
    - ALS to Ulysses Simpson Grant, 1875 Sep 25, Jackson, Mississippi; concerning the Mississippi crisis of 1875; on verso is note to Attorney General signed by Grant, 1875 Sep 27 (Box 1)
    - ALS to Edwards Pierrepont, 1875 Oct 16, Jackson, Mississippi; concerning the Mississippi crisis of 1875 (Box 1)
  - Bruce, B1andte Kelso, 1841-1898. ALS to Edwards Pierrepont, 1875 Sep no day, Washington D.C.; concerning the Mississippi crisis of 1875; also signed by G. N. Buchanan, James Hill, Albert Richards Hose, Jonathan B. Raymond, and. A. Warner. (Box 1)
  - Chase, G. K. ALS to Edwards Pierrepont, 1877 May 4, Washington D.C.; thanking Pierrepont for place in the Justice Department (Box 1)
  - Conkling, Frederick Augustus, 1816-1891. ALS to Edwards Pierrepont, 1887 Nov 19, New York; concerning the coinage of free silver (Box 1)
  - Conkling, Roscoe, 1829-1888. 37 ALS to Edwards Pierrepont
    - 1869 Jan 30, Washington D.C.; expressing regret at having missed Pierrepont during a call paid to him (Box 1)
    - 1869 Dec 18, Washington D.C.; concerning an appointment to the circuit court in Utica (Box 1)
    - 1870 Feb 1, Washington D.C.; concerning a meeting of the Bar (Box 1)
    - 1870 Feb 27, Washington D.C.; concerning the residence of an appointee (Box 1)
    - 1870 Jul 9, Washington D.C.; ackowledgment of letters received (Box 1)
    - 1870 Nov 19, Utica, N.Y.; concerning patronage and the "health") of the Republican Party (Box 1)
    - 1871 Feb 11, Washington D.C.; concerning Horace Greeley and the upcoming struggle in New York elections (Box 1)
    - 1871 Feb 19, Washington D.C.; concerning the overemphasis given to patronage by Republican party opponents (Box 1)
    - 1871 Apr 13, Washington D.C.; acknowledgment of letter received (Box 1)
    - 1871 Dec 12, Washington D.C.; concerning an article re: Conkling in the Tribune (Box 1)
    - 1872 May 28, Washington D.C.; acknowledgment of letters received (Box 1)
    - 1872 Nov 14, Utica, N.Y.; acknowledgment of a letter (Box 1)
    - 1872 Nov 20, Utica, N.Y.; regrets to a dinner invitation (Box 1)
    - 1872 Dec 16, Washington D.C.; concerning Judge Hunt (Box 1)
    - [1873], New York; regrets to an invitation (Box 1)
    - 1873 Jan 16, Washington D.C.; thank-you note (Box 1)
    - 1873 May 21, Utica, N.Y.; concerning Pierrepont's declension of the Russian mission (Box 1)
    - 1873 May 31, Utica, N.Y.; invitation to visit (Box 1)
    - 1873 Sep 21, Utica, N.Y.; invitation to visit (Box 1)
    - 1873 Dec 12, Washington D.C.; concerning a meeting with Pierrepont (Box 1)
    - 1875 Feb 5, Washington D.C.; acknowledgment of letters (Box 1)
    - 1875 Apr 29, Utica, N.Y.; congratulations on Pierrepont's appointment to the cabinet (Box 1)
    - 1875 Nov 8, Utica, N.Y.; expressing satisfaction at election results (Box 1)
    - 1876 Jan 18, Washington D.C.; acceptance of an invitation (Box 1)
    - 1876 Oct 20, Utica, N.Y.; concerning the forthcoming election (Box 1)
    - 1877 Feb 8, Washington D.C; concerning the results of the contested election (Box 1)
    - 1877 Mar 27, Utica, N.Y.; concerning recent cabinet appointments and the possibility of Pierrepont's remaining in London (Box 1)
    - 1877 May 12, Utica, N.Y.; concerning a projected visit to England and Grant's popularity in the United States (Box 1)
    - 1877 Jul 11, London; acknowledgment of favors received during visit to England (Box 1)
    - 1877 Jul no day, London; acknowledgment of favors received during visit to England (Box 1)
    - 1878 Mar 14, Washington D.C.; acknowledgment of letter (Box 1)
    - 1878 Oct 4, Utica, N.Y.; acknowledgment of letter (Box 1)
    - 1879 May 3, Washington D.C.; acknowledgment of letter (Box 1)
    - 1881 no month no day, Washington D.C.; arranging a meeting (Box 1)
    - 1881 Jan 7, Washington D.C.; acknowledgment of a letter (Box 1)
    - 1881 Jan 25, Washington D.C.; acknowledgment of a telegram (Box 1)
    - No date, Washington D.C.; regrets to a dinner invitation (Box 1)
  - Dedrick, W. W. Telegram to Edwards Pierrepont, 1875 Sep 8, Jackson, Mississippi; concerning the Mississippi crisis of 1875 (Box 1)
  - Dix, John Adams, 1798-1879. 2 ALS to Edwards Pierrepont
    - 1867 Feb 2, Paris; concerning his ministry in France, the movement against President Johnson, and the New York State Constitutional Convention (Box 1)
    - 1876 Nov 5, New York; concerning the Hayes-Tilden election (Box 1)
  - Dyer, David Patterson, 1838-1924. Telegram to Edwards Pierrepont, 1875 Dec 11, St. Louis, Missouri; concerning an appointment (Box 1)
  - Evarts, Allen Wardner, 1848-1939. ALS to Edwards Pierrepont, 1877 Aug 2, Liverpool; expressing appreciation of Pierrepont's kindness during his visit to England (Box 1)
  - Evarts, William Maxwell, 1818-1901.
    - ALS to E. H. Carmick, 1880 Jan 23, Washington D.C.; concerning the claim of Albert Speyers against the Mexican government (Box 1)
    - 69 ALS: & telegrams to Edwards Pierrepont
      - 1857 Aug 14, Windsor, Vermont; concerning a visit to Windsor (Box 1)
      - 1860 Feb 25, New York; concerning the nominations of Stephen A. Douglas and William. H. Seward for president (Box 1)
      - 1860 Jul 18, New York; concerning projected visits to Windsor (Box 1)
      - 1860 Aug 10, Windsor, Vermont; concerning a visit to Windsor (Box 1)
      - 1860 Aug 21, Windsor, Vermont; urging Pierrepont to come to Windsor (Box 1)
      - 1861 Aug 5, Windsor, Vermont; urging Pierrepont to come to Windsor (Box 1)
      - 1862 Jun 23, New York; concerning the passage of a bankrupt bill (Box 1)
      - 1862 Jul 10, Windsor, Vermont; concerning the courts and Pierrepont's visit to Windsor (Box 1)
      - 1862 Jul 15, Windsor, Vermont; concerning the war and the necessity of change in the administration (Box 1)
      - 1862 Aug 2, Windsor, Vermont; concerning the danger of the administration's course (Box 1)
      - 1862 Sep 1, Windsor, Vermont; concerning politics and a visit to Windsor (Box 1)
      - 1864 Mar 8, Paris; concerning his semi-official mission to England (Box 1)
      - 1864 Apr 27, London; concerning his semi-official mission to England (Box 1)
      - 1867 Jun 22, New York; concerning the Surratt case and Pierrepont's letters (Box 1)
      - 1867 Aug 28, New York; concerning the cabinet (Box 1)
      - 1867 Sep 2, New York; concerning the New York State Constitutional Convention (Box 1)
      - 1868 Apr 16, Washington D.C.; concerning the impeachment of Andrew Johnson (Box 1)
      - 1868 Apr 21, Washington D.C.; concerning the impeachment of Andrew Johnson (Box 1)
      - 1868 May 6, Washington D.C.; concerning the impeachment of Andrew Johnson (Box 1)
      - 1868 Oct 24, Washington D.C.; concerning Grant's election (Box 1)
      - 1868 Nov 20, Washington D.C.; concerning the forwarding of letters to him (Box 1)
      - 1868 Nov 24, Washington D.C.; concerning Yale College (Box 1)
      - 1868 Nov 24, Washington D.C.; concerning his work as Attorney General (Box 1)
      - 1868 Dec 25, Washington D.C.; Christmas greetings (Box 1)
      - 1869 Jan 9, Washington D.C.; concerning Evarts's position with the new administration (Box 1)
      - 1869 Feb 7, Washington D.C.; concerning Grant's cabinet (Box 1)
      - 1869 Feb 24, Washington D.C.; concerning his retirement from the cabinet (Box 1)
      - 1869 Mar 22, Washington D.C.; concerning a missed meeting (Box 1)
      - 1869 Mar 22, Washington D.C.; concerning a meeting (Box 1)
      - 1869 Mar 24, Washington D.C.; concerning Pierrepont's coming to Washington (Box 1)
      - 1869 Mar 29, Washington D.C.; discouraging Pierrepont's coming to Washington (Box 1)
      - 1869 Apr 12, Washington D.C.; concerning the appointment of James C. Jackson as District Attorney (Box 1)
      - 1869 Jul 13, New York; concerning Susie Owen's loss of position in the Treasury Department (Box 1)
      - 1869 Jul 29, Windsor, Vermont; proposing to see Pierrepont in New York (Box 1)
      - 1869 Aug 4, New York; letter of introduction for Charles Blackis (Box 1)
      - 1869 Aug 16, Windsor, Vermont; concerning the Pratt case and the political situation (Box 1)
      - 1869 Oct 29, New York; concerning the appointment of Charles Blackis (Box 1)
      - 1870 Sep 13, Windsor, Vermont; urging Pierrepont to accept the English mission if offered (Box 1)
      - 1870 Sep 29, New York; concerning an unaswered letter (Box 1)
      - 1872 Feb 3, London; concerning American politics and the British situation (Box 1)
      - 1872 Jun 21, Paris; concerning the presidential nominations (Box 1)
      - 1872 Jul 17, Geneva; concerning the Arbitration Tribunal (Box 1)
      - 1872 Aug 23, Geneva; concerning the American political scene (Box 1)
      - 1874 Feb 2, New York; proposing a meeting (Box 1)
      - 1874 Jul 1, New York; concerning an address of Pierrepont's (Box 1)
      - 1874 Aug 18, New York; concerning his daughter's wedding (Box 1)
      - 1875 Jul 28, Windsor, Vermont; concerning a proposed visit to Windsor (Box 1)
      - 1875 Aug 5, Windsor, Vermont; concerning a law case (Box 1)
      - 1875 Sep 11, Windsor, Vermont; concerning applications for patents (Box 1)
      - 1875 Oct 21, New York; concerning a Circuit Court Judgeship (Box 1)
      - 1875 Oct 23, New York; telegram concerning Johnson's appointment to the Judgeship (Box 1)
      - 1876 May 23, New York; congratulating Pierrepont on his appointment as Minister to Great Britain (Box 1)
      - 1876 Sep 11, Windsor, Vermont; concerning the political situation and Evarts's escape from nomination (Box 1)
      - 1877 May 1, Washington D.C.; concerning the Hayes-Tilden election (Box 1)
      - 1878 Sep 29, Washington D.C.; concerning the coming Congressional elections (Box 1)
      - 1878 Mar 21, Washington D.C.; concerning Major Bundy and his paper (Box 1)
      - 1878 Oct 31, Washington D.C.; concerning a meeting about Bundy's paper (Box 1)
      - 1878 Nov 6, Washington D.C.; concerning Maj. Bundy and his paper (Box 1)
      - 1878 Nov 9, Washington D.C.; concerning Maj. Bundy and his paper (Box 1)
      - 1878 Nov 12, Washington D.C.; concerning politics (Box 1)
      - 1878 Nov 17, Washington D.C.; concerning Maj. Bundy and his paper (Box 1)
      - 1878 Dec 29; Washington D.C.; concerning Maj. Bundy and his paper (Box 1)
      - 1879 Mar 8, Washington D.C.; concerning a meeting with Pierrepont (Box 1)
      - 1879 Dec 15, Washington D.C.; concerning a meeting with Grant (Box 1)
      - 1882 Aug 22, Windsor, Vermont; concerning Chief Justice Waite (Box 1)
      - 1886 Sep 13, Windsor, Vermont; concerning an illness (Box 1)
      - 1889 Feb 18, Washington D.C.; concerning the coming Harrison administration (Box 1)
      - 1890 Feb 16, no place; concerning the state of Pierrepont's health (Box 1)
      - No date, Windsor, Vermont; concerning a letter of Evarts's (Box 1)
    - ALS to Frederick William Seward, 1862 Mar 15, New York; concerning a prisoner of war, Andrew Low (Box 1)
    - ALS to Edwin McMasters Stanton, 1862 Mar 15, New York; concerning a prisoner of war, Andrew Low (Box 1)
  - Fish, Hamilton, 1808-1893. ALS to Edwards Pierrepont, 1875 Sep 10, Garrison-on-Hudson, New York; concerning the Mississippi crisis of 1875 (Box 2)
  - French, Ezra Bartlett, 1810-1880. ALS to Edwards Pierrepont, 1876 Apr 12, Washington D.C.; concerning a sum deposited for the use of the Special Commission on Prisoners of State [enclosed is a copy of ALS John Adams Dix and Edwards Pierrepont to Edwin McMasters Stanton, 1862 Mar 27, Washington D.C.] (Box 2)
  - Grant, Ulysses Simpson, Pres. U.S., 1822-1885
    - 2 ALS to Edwards Pierrepont
      - 1875 Sep 13, Long Branch, New Jersey; concerning the Mississippi crisis of 1875 (Box 2)
      - 1876 Jul 29, Washington D.C.; concerning the Chicago "Whiskey Ring" (Box 2)
    - 2 Proclamations commanding the cessation of disorder in Mississippi
      - 1874 Dec 21, Washington D.C. (Box 2)
      - 1875 Sep no day, Washington D.C. [Also signed by Secretary of State Hamilton Fish] (Box 2)
  - Grant, Ulysses Simpson, Jr. 1852-1929. ALS to Edwards Pierrepont, 1876 Feb 21, Washington D.C.; concerning the Mississippi crisis of 1875 (Box 2)
  - Guthrie, J. B. Telegram to Edwards Pierrepont, 1875 Sep 14, Vicksburg, Mississippi; concerning the Mississippi crisis of 1875 (Box 2)
  - Luckey, Levi P. [Secretary to Grant]. ALS to Edwards Pierrepont, 1875 Sep 9, Washington D.C.; concerning the Mississippi crisis of 1875 (Box 2)
  - Noonan, W. Telegram to Edwards Pierrepont, 1875 Sep 24, Jackson, Mississippi; concerning Mississippi crisis of 1875 (Box 2)
  - Pierrepont, Edwards, 1817-1892
    - ALS to David Patterson Dyer, 1875 Dec 7, Washington D.C.; Justice Department business (Box 2)
    - ALS to Ezra Bartlett French, 1876 Apr 13, no place; concerning a sum deposited for the use of the Special Commission on Prisoners of State (Box 2)
    - 3 AL & ALS to Ulysses Simpson Grant
      - 1875 Dec 13, Washington D.C.; concerning Chicago "Whiskey Ring" (Box 2)
      - 1875 Dec 14, Washington D.C.; concerning Chicago "Whiskey Ring" (Box 2)
      - 1876 Aug 22, London; concerning Chicago "Whiskey Ring" (Box 2)
  - Reynolds, Thomas C. Telegram to Edwards Pierrepont, 1875 Dec 14, St. Louis, Missouri; concerning an appointment (Box 2)
  - Seward, Frederick William, 1830-1915. ALS to William Maxwell Evarts, 1862 Feb 8, Washington D.C.; concerning Andrew Low, a prisoner of war [enclosed is copy of letter from William Henry Seward to Justin Dimick, 1862 Feb 8, Washington D.C.] (Box 2)
  - Stanton, Edwin McMasters, 1814-1869. 9 ALS & telegrams to Edwards Pierrepont
    - 1862 Jan 7, Washington D.C.; concerning the situation in the country (Box 3)
    - 1862 Feb 23, Washington D.C.; concerning the appointment of Pierrepont to the Special Commission on Prisoners of State (Box 3)
    - 1862 Apr 5, Washington D.C.; concerning prisoners of war (Box 3)
    - 1862 Apr 11, Washington D.C.; Commission business (Box 3)
    - 1862 Apr 18, Washington D.C.; Commission business (Box 3)
    - 1862 Sep 8, Washington D.C.; concerning the arrests of prisoners (Box 3)
    - 1863 Oct 2, Washington D.C.; concerning Major General Banks (Box 3)
    - 1864 Jul 5, Washington D.C.; concerning acts of General Dix under direct orders from the President (Box 3)
    - 1864 Jul 15, Washington D.C.; concerning thr proceedings against General Dix (Box 3)
  - Warner, A. Telegram to Edwards Pierrepont, 1875 Sep 13, Jackson, Mississippi; concerning the Mississippi crisis of 1875 (Box 3)
- Additional Material, Accession 2004-M-003
  This accession consists of correspondence written and received by Edwards Pierrepont; financial records; legal documents; and printed material, which document his career as a New York lawyer and judge, United States attorney for the southern district of New York, United States attorney general in Grant's cabinet, and ambassador to the Court of St. James.
  The correspondence is arranged in chronological order; documents are arranged alphabetically by topic and/or title.
  - Correspondence [incoming/outgoing]
    - 1851-1855 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1856-1859 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1861-1864 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1865-1869 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1870-1875 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1876 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1877-1879 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1885, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Documents
    - Agreement between Monsieur Pierrepont and Hiram Malott [sale of farm] (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Finances [checks, receipts, etc.], 1856-1857, 1863-1864, 1871, 1875-1876, 1882, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Goodenough vs. Rarey [minutes], 1863 April 29 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Invitation to meet Alfred C. Coxe [U.S. district judge for the northern district of New York], 1882 December 4 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - "Organization and by-laws of the New York...Steam Company", undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Power of attorney for Samuel A. Willoughby, 1851 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Speech [handwritten copy of "...the Yale speech before the Alumni from the New Haven Morning News," letter to the editor on topic of revenues owed to Yale], 1887 June 20 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Speeches [printed publications], 1837, 1869-1871 (Box 1, Folder 16)